So ensure knowledge transfer for project
continuity, also called in the PIMBOC,
manage project knowledge.
So it's important that we use and
contribute to organizational knowledge,
organizational learning.
So we must access and use knowledge
already retained.
So our lessons learned repository is one
of the play.
places where, again, think SharePoint,
where we can access information,
that's huge.
Why would you reinvent the wheel?
And why wouldn't you access what has gone
well?
What hasn't gone well on previous similar
recently completed project files?
It only makes sense.
Learn from what has happened before.
What went well, let's do that again.
What didn't go well, let's not do that
again so we can implement preventive
action right away okay we will also
contribute to organizational learning we
are going to document on our own project
we will document what's going well what's
not going well now what we create what
stays in our hot little hands till the end
of the project is our
lessons learned register
registers stay in our
hot hot little hands.
This will document everything going well,
not going well on our project.
All right.
So types of knowledge that we're going to
document.
We have explicit.
So explicit, those are
things easily codified that
we can easily document
like charts, reports, graphs.
we can create diagrams.
Okay, so numbering, you know, how things
are going, for example.
Easy to document.
Whereas tacit, those are usually
intangible things that are not so easily
documented and often are not documented,
but it's our job to actually try to get
this information like experience,
beliefs, feelings, skills, know-how.
Why is it when we do a specific type of
project?
We get to a certain point in the project,
for example, where we start to get
kickback from the stakeholders,
start getting, you know, some questions.
Why are we doing this?
Or whatever the case is.
We need to actually find out
the feeling, What is causing the
stakeholders to start to feel
the way they do as an example?
That's tacit knowledge that is not often
documented.
So we need to create an atmosphere where
stakeholders, including our team members,
feel comfortable to share beliefs,
feelings, know-how experiences what
they're going through so we can learn from
them.
If we keep getting kickback from
stakeholders, they're objecting to certain
things at a specific point in
the project, let's document
that so we can make corrections
and not have it happen again.
So these are all
different feelings, beliefs,
tacit knowledge that we
also need to document.
So definitely keep that in mind.
It's often overlooked.
All right.
So to ensure project continuity that we're
transferring knowledge throughout the
project we have knowledge that will exist
on three levels individual knowledge okay
what each individual team member
stakeholder Sme that we're using might
know as well as overall project knowledge
and above that organizational knowledge
all of these things
can actually benefit the
entire organization not
just the projects, okay?
Tools that we can use to
transfer knowledge network,
we're going to yap with other
people in the organization.
It can be internal or external,
all right?
Conducting and facilitating meetings.
We learn things that way.
We can teach that way, share knowledge
that way.
We can do work shadowing, mentoring,
pairing.
These are all ways of sharing knowledge.
as well as actually giving informal or
formal training.
All right.
So a couple of things I want to point out.
Our lessons learned register.
So I've mentioned this before.
This register stays in our hot little
hands.
This is everything
going well, not going well
on our project that
we're going to document.
So it is a project artifact document we
are creating for our project.
Whereas OPAs, remember those
organizations, process assets that we pull
from and use like SharePoint would be the
lessons learned repository what has gone
well what it has not gone well on previous
similar recently completed projects that
we want to learn from once our project is
done our Lessons Learn register will
become part of the
OPEs we will archive this
information so we can be
used on the next project.
So we will share knowledge throughout the
project.
We're going to use knowledge that's been
documented.
We're going to create and share knowledge
that we create on our projects.